Semen Protsenko

Software Engineer

Austin, TX, 78745 \Box +1 (512) 986-2526 ☑ joe.skb7@gmail.com in sam-protsenko-491b311b ioe-skb7



Summary

Embedded software engineer with more than 10 years of professional experience. Main area of expertise is Linux kernel, bootloaders, firmwares and system level user space programming on ARM-based devices. For the last 5 years has been contributing to open-source projects and been involved with upstreaming activity. Has prior background in cross-platform applications development, algorithms and electronics. Active member of open-source community, mentor, speaker.

Experience

2020-Present Software Engineer, Linaro

Team: Linaro Consumer Group, Kernel Team.

Role: Supporting the WinLink's E850-96 board.

Activities: Board bring up, enabling it in mainline kernel and U-Boot, upstreaming.

2018–2020 **Team Lead**, *GlobalLogic*, Kyiv, Ukraine

Project: Texas Instruments (Linaro assignee for LCG).

Role: Supporting the BEAGLEBOARD X15 board and upstreaming work.

- O Porting Android to a new board and upstreaming it with a small team: [1]
- Adopting VPN from upstream kernel in AOSP: [2]
- Implementing Android 10 boot sequence: [3]
- O Running Android 10 with mainline kernel on BEAGLEBOARD X15

2012–2018 **Software Engineer**, *GlobalLogic*, Kyiv, Ukraine

Projects: Texas Instruments (directly and as Linaro assignee for LEG and LMG), others.

Role: Platform development in Linux kernel and bootloaders, upstreaming.

- Supporting Android kernel on TI OMAP4/OMAP5 SoC
- Board bring ups, bug fixing, migrating to new kernel versions
- Implementing and supporting device drivers: [4]
- Maintaining boot sequence and fastboot in U-Boot: [5]
- Implementing XIP boot from NOR flash (automotive)
- System boot time optimizations (automotive)

2009–2012 **Software Developer**, *AlterEGO*, Kramatorsk, Ukraine

Role: Cross-platform software design and coding (C++/Qt).

Activities: Implementing optical character recognition, game clients, interaction with web, apps for automating diverse tasks.

Education

2008–2009 Master of Science in Computer Aided Engineering,

Donbas State Mechanical Engineering Academy, Kramatorsk, Ukraine

2004–2008 Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering Technology,

Donbas State Mechanical Engineering Academy, Kramatorsk, Ukraine

Computer skills

Languages C, C++, Bash

Projects Linux kernel, U-Boot, Android

CPUs ARM32, AArch64, x86

MCUs AM57x, AM65x, STM32,

MSP430

Tools GCC, GDB, Make, Git, Vim

Hardware JTAG, scope, logical analyzer

Languages

Ukrainian Native or bilingual proficiency

English Professional working proficiency

Other Activities

2011-Today Maintainer of "INSTEAD" Debian package: [6]

2015–Today Active member on StackOverflow (>10k reputation): [7]

2019 Organizer of "Root Linux Conference" in Kyiv: [8]

2018–Today Creator and instructor of Linux kernel course: [9]

2017–2019 Speaker at Linaro and GlobalLogic events

References

- [1] https://android-review.googlesource.com/q/author:protsenko
- [2] https://connect.linaro.org/resources/bkk19/bkk19-414/
- [3] https://connect.linaro.org/resources/san19/san19-217/
- [4] https://git.kernel.org/pub/scm/linux/kernel/git/torvalds/linux.git/log/?qt=author&q=protsenko
- [5] https://gitlab.denx.de/u-boot/u-boot/-/commits/master?search=
 protsenko
- [6] http://packages.debian.org/sid/instead
- [7] https://stackoverflow.com/users/3866447/sam-protsenko
- [8] https://linux.globallogic.com/
- [9] https://github.com/joe-skb7/kernel-lectures